bearnecessities.org 2019-03-01

# Privacy Policy

Privacy Policy
Last Revised: December 8, 2014
This Privacy Policy describes how Bear Necessities Pediatric Cancer Foundation (“Bear Necessities”) treats
information that Bear Necessities collects and receives from you through www.bearnecessities.org (the
“Site”) and through other aspects of Bear Necessities’ business, including offline. This Privacy Policy
together with the Terms of Use govern your use of the Site.
1.        Acceptance of Privacy Policy
Each time you access, use, or browse the Site or provide personal information to Bear Necessities offline,
you signify your acceptance of the then-current Privacy Policy. If you do not accept this Privacy Policy,
you are not authorized to provide information to Bear Necessities or use the Site and must discontinue use
of the Site immediately.
Should the Privacy Policy be materially revised, Bear Necessities will post the changes on the Site and the
new Privacy Policy will be effective immediately upon posting and will apply only to information
collected thereafter, unless we provide notice or have other communications with you. You can determine
when the Privacy Policy was last revised by referring to the “Last Revised” legend at the top of this page.
2.        Types of Information Collected
We may collect personal information from you including, without limitation, non-public information about
you that helps Bear Necessities identify you, such as first and last name, organization name, birth date,
email address, home and business addresses, telephone number, credit or debit card information, billing
address, and other non-public information. We may also collect personal information about you including,
without limitation, medical and family information, from hospitals or medical providers that have
confirmed to us they have received consent from you for such disclosure.
We may collect non-personal information about your use of the Site such as your IP address, usage
statistics, browsing history, country location, type of computer operating system you use (e.g., Microsoft
Windows or Mac OS), the type of browser you use (e.g., Firefox, Chrome, Internet Explorer), and the
domain name of your internet service provider.
3.        How We Collect Information
We may collect personal information from you when you:
•    Sign up to receive announcements or newsletters;
•    Sign up to participate in or donate to runs, marathons, or other activities;
•    Make a donation or contribution to Bear Necessities;
•    Sign up or attend events;
•    Volunteer;
•    Purchase any goods on the Site;
•    Submit a grant or support service proposal or sign up to receive a grant or support services; and
•    Communicate with Bear Necessities via email or offline.
Personal information collected by Bear Necessities may be stored and processed in the United States in
accordance with the laws of the United States. By using the Site and submitting your personal information
to Bear Necessities offline, you expressly consent to the storage and processing of your personal
information in the United States or elsewhere in accordance with the laws of the United States.
Revised 12/8/14

Bear Necessities automatically receives and records non-personal information on our server logs from your
browser as well as through other analysis of the Site. We also may collect information using cookies, web
beacons or similar technologies, or through third parties using similar technologies. A cookie is a piece of
data stored on your computer. When you visit the Site, your web browser may store cookies on your
computer, which will better enable you to navigate the Site upon return. You may use the Site even if you
choose to reject or delete the cookies. Cookies also may be used by some of the other websites for which a
link is placed on the Site.
4.        How We Use Your Information
We may use the information we collect:
•    To process and respond to your requests and inquiries and provide services to you.
•    To alert you to new developments, special events, programs, runs, marathons, grants, support services,
     products or services.
•    To send announcements and newsletters, and to provide you with personalized content in the
     newsletters.
•    For the purposes for which you provided the information.
•    To monitor and analyze information regarding your browsing and viewing preferences and to diagnose
     problems of the Site.
•    To analyze our users’ demographics and interests.
•    For administration and improvement of the Site and to enhance the user experience.
•    For fraud prevention, internal operations, legal compliance, and other public purposes.
•    To enforce the Terms of Use.
In the case of personal information about you provided to us by hospitals or medical providers, we may use
such information in the ways we are informed by the hospital or medical provider you have permitted.
5.        Communications with You
You authorize Bear Necessities to transmit email to you or telephone you to respond to your
communications, and provide information to you about new developments, special events, programs, runs,
marathons, grants, support services, products and services.
You have the option to not receive further promotional communications from Bear Necessities.
Unsubscribe instructions are included in each promotional email from Bear Necessities. You may also
send an email to office@bearnecessities.org, mail to the postal address 55 West Wacker Drive, Suite 1100
Chicago, IL 60601, or call us at (312) 214-1200. Please note that unsubscribe requests may take up to ten
(10) days to become effective. You may not opt out of receiving communications regarding your dealings
with the Site or technical information about the Site.
6.        Information Sharing with Third Parties
Except as provided below, Bear Necessities does not share the information it collects from you with others
without your permission.
We do not disclose or sell personal information of our donors with any third party.
Revised 12/8/14

Bear Necessities may disclose the information it collects to others:
     (i) for purposes of outsourcing to or receiving assistance for one or more of the functions described in
     the Terms or this Privacy Policy from third parties who work on behalf of or with Bear Necessities
     under confidentiality or similar agreements including service providers, agents, vendors, partners,
     advocates, researchers, consultants, volunteers, and affiliates;
     (ii) to confirm or update information provided by you, including by combining information you
     provide with information from other services such as public records;
     (iii) for any of Bear Necessities’ research projects performed by it or a third party on its behalf or under
     its supervision;
     (iv) in the event of any reorganization, merger, sale, joint venture, assignment, transfer or disposition
     of all or any portion of Bear Necessities’ business or operations (including without limitation in
     connection with bankruptcy or any similar proceedings);
     (v) as otherwise authorized by you; or
     (vi) in the case of personal information about you provided to us by hospitals or medical providers, for
     the purposes we are informed by the hospital or medical provider you have permitted.
We also may share your information in response to a subpoena or legal order, when we believe you have
acted in violation of the Terms, to investigate, prevent or take action regarding suspected illegal activities,
fraud or potential threats, or exercise legal rights or defend against claims, when we believe that doing so
may protect your safety or the safety of Bear Necessities or others, or as otherwise permitted or required by
law.
We may share non-personally identifiable, anonymized or aggregate information with third parties.
Additionally, we may take personally identifiable information and de-identify it and share it in a de-
identified or aggregated form with third parties, advertisers and/or business partners in order to analyze
Site usage, demographics, or interests, improve our products or services, improve our user experience, or
for similar purposes. We will not re-identify such data and we will ask our contracting parties to agree to
keep the data in its de-identified form.
7.         Children
Bear Necessities does not knowingly collect personal information from children under age 13. If you are
under age 13, you are not permitted to use the Site or to submit any personal information to the Bear
Necessities offline or on the Site. If you are between 13 and 17 years of age, you may visit the Site, but
you may not submit any personal information. If we become aware that a Site user is under age 18 and
has provided personal information, we will take steps to remove his or her personal information from our
files. If you are a parent or guardian and believe Bear Necessities may have inadvertently collected
personal information from your child, please notify Bear Necessities immediately by sending an email to
office@bearnecessities.org.
In the case of personal information about you provided to us by hospitals or medical providers, such
information may be collected about children under the age of 17 with their parent or legal guardian’s
consent, if we have received confirmation from the hospitals or medical providers that such information
was collected with the parent or legal guardian’s consent.
Revised 12/8/14

8.        Protection of Personal Information
Bear Necessities uses reasonable administrative, physical and electronic security measures to protect
against the loss, misuse and alteration of personal information. No transmission of data over the internet is
guaranteed to be completely secure. It may be possible for third parties not under the control of Bear
Necessities to intercept or access transmissions or private communications unlawfully. While we strive to
protect personal information, neither Bear Necessities nor our service providers can ensure or warrant the
security of any information you transmit to us over the internet. Any such transmission is at your own risk.
9.        Updating Your Information
You are responsible for keeping your information current. You may update your information by contacting
us at office@bearnecessities.org. We will use reasonable efforts to process any change you make;
provided, however, that requests to delete information are subject to Bear Necessities’ internal reporting,
processing and retention policies and all applicable legal obligations.
10.       Links
You may have the opportunity to follow links on the Site to other sites that may be of interest to you. Bear
Necessities endeavors to only link to reputable organizations. Because other sites may not be hosted or
controlled by Bear Necessities, we are not responsible for the privacy practices of those sites or the content
provided thereon. Therefore, the privacy policies with respect to other sites may differ from those
applicable to the Site. We encourage you to review the privacy policies of each other site. This Privacy
Policy only applies to information collected and maintained by Bear Necessities.
QUESTIONS? If you have any questions or concerns regarding this Privacy Policy, please contact us at
office@bearnecessities.org. Please note that email communications may not be secure. Accordingly, you
should not include personal or other sensitive information in your email correspondence to the Site or Bear
Necessities.
Revised 12/8/14
